*****************************

THE COMBAT COLLECTION

music for violent video games

by

JOHN LEONARD FRENCH

*****************************

IMPORTANT - for best results with this guide, disable text wrapping or use the combat collection .pdf file, available with your download or at www.johnleonardfrench.com

*****************************

The complete Combat Collection comprises orchestral epics, ethnic rhythms and iconic themes for games with violence and action at their core. Specially created for game developers, the collection features full tracks and seamless loops all designed for combat, action and adventure games.

High quality audio. Each track is provided as a CD quality 16bit, 44.1khz, uncompressed .wav file that’s ready for import, normalised to preserve bit depth and professionally mastered to provide the very best sound.

Gapless loops. Looped tracks have been created to cycle perfectly, in exact sync, with correct reverb tails and at the precise signal zero crossing point. Meaning no pops, silences, clicks, sudden changes or other unwanted noises, just great music.

Fascinating instruments. The combat collection uses some wonderfully rare and unique instruments such as the hang drum, Darabuka and lapsteel however it really wouldn’t be a combat collection without an anvil, 
would it now?

Feedback and suggestions for future packs are welcome.

Enjoy,

John Leonard French 


support  |  feedback  |  commissions  |  requests

www.johnleonardfrench.com  
info@johnleonardfrench.com 
@johnlfrench

© 2013

*****************************

Track List

Track				Description						Key	Tempo	T-Sig*	Time	Size	Starter	PRO

Ambience 1 Ethnic Full		Ethnic drums with melodic hang drum			-	90 bpm	4/4	2:03	21.6 mb		yes
Ambience 1 Ethnic Loop		Seamless loop without hang drum				-	90 bpm	4/4	1:25	15.1 mb		yes
Ambience 2 Ethnic Full		Middle eastern marketplace				A min	85 bpm	3/4	1:41 	17.9 mb		yes
Ambience 3 Wasteland Full	Distant violin and piano in an arid wasteland		C min	75 bpm	3/4	1:14	13.1		yes
Ambience 4 Loop			Seamless percussion loop with string bed		C	120 bpm	4/4	0:48	8.5 mb		yes
Ambience 4 Layers		x3 Layer parts for dynamic crossfading			C	120 bpm	4/4	-	-		yes
Big Battle 1 Full		Frantic orchestral epic					D min	130 bpm	4/4	1.39	17.6 mb		yes
Big Battle 1 Loop**		Seamless loop						D min	130 bpm	4/4	1:32	16.3 mb		yes
Big Battle 2 Full		Large scale battle with orchestral stabs		D min	170 bpm	3/4	1:41 	17.9 mb	yes	yes
Big Battle 2 Loop**		Seamless loop						D min	170 bpm	3/4	1:39	17.6 mb		yes
Big Battle 3 Full		Gritty battle piece with ripped brass			D min	90 bpm	4/4	2:33	26.8 mb		yes
Big Battle 4 Full		Pounding timpani and distorted brass			C min	110 bpm	3/4	1:26	15.2 mb		yes
Big Battle 4 Loop**		Seamless loop						C min	110 bpm	3/4	1:12	12.7 mb		yes
Close Combat 1 Loop		Hand to hand, one on one percussion			-	190 bpm	3/4	1:04	11.4 mb	yes	yes
Close Combat 2 Loop		Circle of death! Simple, duelling percussion loop	-	160 bpm	3/4	0:36	6.4 mb		yes
Espionage 1 Loop 1		Full instrumentation					B	70 bpm	4/4	0:54	9.7 mb	yes	yes
Espionage 1 Loop 2		Simple instrumentation					B	70 bpm	4/4	0:27	4.8 mb		yes
Espionage 2 Loop		Mysterious pedal bass piece with sound design		D	60 bpm	4/4	1:04	11.3		yes
Espionage 3 Loop		Drum loop with a dark synth bed and bass pedal		E min	140 bpm	4/4	1:29	15.7 mb		yes
Main Theme 1			‘The Combat Collection’ title theme			A min	105 bpm	3/4	2:56	31.1 mb	yes	yes
Main Theme 2			‘Brothers in arms’ tragic theme				D	70 bpm	4/4	1:15	13.3 mb		yes
Main Theme 3			‘Phoenix Rising’ building piano theme			A min	130 bpm	3/4	1:50	19.4 mb		yes
Pursuit 1 Full			Controlled continuos chase music with a manic vibe	D min	80 bpm	4/4 	1:36	17.1 mb	yes	yes
Pursuit 1 Loop**		Seamless loop without intro				D min	80 bpm	4/4	1:24	14.8 mb		yes
Pursuit 2 Full			Chaotic chase music with mad percussion			C min	190 bpm	4/4	0:54	9.6 mb		yes
Pursuit 2 Loop**		Seamless loop						C min	190 bpm	4/4	0:50	8.9 mb		yes
Defeats				x3 Short themes for deaths or serious moments		-	-	-	-	-		yes
Victories			x3 Short themes for victories and level ups		-	-	-	-	-		yes
Horror scare long		Scratching violins with build up			-	-	-	0:22	3.9 mb		yes
Horror scare short		Without build up					-	-	-	0:11	2 mb		yes
Quest SFX - bongos		x6 Waypoint / objective sounds				-	-	-	-	-		yes
Quest SFX - snares		x5 Waypoint / objective sounds				-	-	-	-	-		yes
BONUS TRACKS			x3 Bonus tracks, Ambient cave / Main theme / Battle	-	-	-	-	-		yes

* Time signature
** Includes start / end parts

Key

FULL: 		A complete piece of music with a start and finish.
SIMPLE:	Variation of a full piece with reduced or simpler instrumentation and style.
LOOP: 		Can be looped seamlessly to form a longer piece of music.
START:		A starting segment for use with looped music. Add after before a looped file starts
END:		An ending segment for use with looped music. Add after a looped file finishes. 
		(May also be suitable as a victory / level up cue)
LONG/SHORT:	Indicating longer and edited versions of the same piece when available.

*****************************

Using loops

The looped files in the collection include the reverb tail at the end of the piece and are looped in exact sync at the zero crossing point. This means the looping section will be seamless. To further enhance looped files, selected tracks include ‘START’ and ‘END’ files to bookend the looped file, creating a longer looping track that still has a start and end section. When importing music as .mp3, looping is not usually recommended unless gapless mp3 looping is available. This is because the compression process may sometimes remove samples creating a gap.
Technical information

File type: 		.wav - waveform audio - PCM uncompressed
Channels:		2 - stereo
Stereo pan law:		Equal power (no attenuation for centre pan)
Bit depth:		16 bit (dithered from 24 bit)
Bit rate:		1,411,200
Sample rate:		44.1 Khz
Normalised:		yes, to -1db

IMPORTANT: all of the music recordings contained within this pack are protected under contract and may be used only for the purposes and within the conditions contained in the END USER LICENCE AGREEMENT. Copyright remains with the author at all times and tracks are provided for synchronisation within projects via non exclusive licence. No music from this pack, either full or in part may be sub-licenced, sold or provided for use to a third party, played publicly or sampled to create a new musical product. 

Crediting the author

By using this music in your project, there is no obligation to credit the author however should you wish to do so then please observe the following. Credit is kindly appreciated.

Name:	 	John Leonard French
Credit:		‘Music courtesy of’, ‘Music provided by’ etc.
IMDB:		http://www.imdb.com/name/nm3623682/

Support / tutorials

info@johnleonardfrench.com 
www.johnleonardfrench.com 

*****************************

